Where there are now two land masses, there once was just one.
这里肯定以前是一块大陆 现在变成了两个大陆块
The Book of Leaves has to be here.
叶之书肯定就在这儿
Take whatever steps are necessary to find our spy. Do it quickly.
不惜一切手段找到探子 行动要快
It is God's will to break Lorenzo and all who support him.
摧毁洛伦佐和所有支持他的人 这是神的旨意
With the exception of Da Vinci, I agree with you.
就达芬奇的部分 我可能有些异议
Those weapons he makes, they could all be ours.
他制造出的武器 反而可以为我们所用
Rome has more men, and the Lord, on its side.
罗马人多势强 天时地利
Well, we've got ten pipe organ muskets
我们有十架管风琴火炮
capable of firing 33 rounds a minute on ours.
一分钟可以连续发射33次
Ten guns? Good to know. Thank you for that.
十架火炮? 谢谢你告诉我
Papers with the papal seal.
盖有罗马密印的信
A list of locations to hide them.
以及藏匿的地点
- Where did you find this?  - Signor Becchi's quarters.
- 你在哪儿找到的?  - 在贝奇先生的住处
The traitor was you.
原来叛徒是你
Lorenzo, this is a mistake.
洛伦佐 这是场误会
Boy.
孩子
One of my huntsmen wishes this decorated.
我的一个猎人想装饰这盾牌
You've a keen eye. Paint it.
你很有天赋 画一下吧
When Leonardo was 14 years old,
莱昂纳多十四岁的时候
his father, Piero, having found little use for the young man,
他的父亲皮耶罗发现他很有天分
gave him a task.
便给他一件工作
Leo spent the next day collecting all manner of strange creatures.
第二天 莱昂捕捉了各种各样生物
And so long did he labor dissecting them
他花了很长时间解剖它们
that the stench was past bearing.
虽然臭味令人难以忍受
But Leonardo didn't notice,
但莱昂纳多并不在意
so great was his love for his art.
他对艺术是多么热爱啊
It's finished, Father! Come see.
我完成了 父亲! 来看看吧
It will suffice.
做得不错
Knowing that the hunting guide would be none the wiser,
瞒着那个猎人
Piero presented him with a new shield,
皮耶罗还给他一块新盾牌
while selling the original one to a vendor
把旧盾牌以一百达科特的价钱
for 100 ducats.
卖给了小贩
And then the vendor resold it to the Duke of Milan himself
后来小贩又以三百达科特的价钱
for 300 ducats.
卖给了米兰公爵
Loath to pass up such a resource,
后来皮耶罗很不情愿地
Piero arranged for his son to be brought under my tutelage.
把他的儿子交给我指导
I paid a finder's fee of 50 ducats.
我给了中间人五十达科特
A bargain, in my estimation.
在我看来非常划算
His father sold you a bastard son.
他父亲卖给你一个小混蛋
Yes. But you know what?
是啊 但你知道吗?
I would trade 100 of you
要是能再有一个他这样的人
to have another one like him on my doorstep.
我愿意拿一百个你们这样的人来换
I think you're drunk, old man.
我觉得你喝多了 老头
And you're jealous, Botticelli.
你是嫉妒吧 波提切利
Tomorrow... I'll be sober.
明天... 我就能醒酒
But you'll still be jealous.
但你还是会嫉妒
You're preoccupied today.
你今天心事重重的
Painting...
作画...
is about... it's about more than just strokes.
不只是用笔画画那样简单
There's perspective.
还要讲究视角
I mean, do I paint you from below...
我是应该从下面的角度画你...
or do I paint you...
还是应该...
from above?
从上面呢?
And then there's symbols.
还要讲究象征
Do I paint you with a dog in your arms?
我要不要画你抱着只狗呢?
It's a symbol of loyalty.
狗是忠诚的象征
Color. How about the particular shade of vermillion...
还有颜色 用一点朱红色...
that I use for the blush of your cheeks?
画你脸颊的红润怎么样?
And the folds of your dress.
还有裙子的褶皱
Should they be...
应该是...
lush and sumptuous...
雍容华贵的...
or stiff and angular?
还是平整带角的?
And perhaps...
或许...
no gown at all.
完全不画礼服
If I was a dutiful servant,
要是我守本分的话
I'd consider the needs of my patron.
我会考虑雇主的要求
But I'm not, so that...
但我不守本分 所以...
That is what I struggle with.
我才心事重重
You can't take your eyes off that.
你一直在看那个
What's so beautiful about it?
它有什么好看的?
It's the same thing I see in you. It's a mystery.
它和你一样 都很神秘
It's a puzzle,
它是个迷
and I will stop at nothing to figure it out.
我会不顾一切地解开它
Francesco.
弗朗西斯科
The walls of my Cappella Maggiore lean and crumble,
我马焦雷教堂的墙都快塌了
just as Rome itself is in disrepair.
就像罗马城一样破败不堪
This place must become a grand palace of the Lord,
我一定要在这建座雄伟的教堂
celebrating his glory in marble
用大理石圣殿
and majestic brushstrokes
和世上最优秀的画作
from the most enlightened hands on earth.
庆祝主的荣耀
I will build a gleaming chapel
我要建一座精美的教堂
with the stories of Christ and Moses frescoed on the ceiling.
在天顶画上基督和摩西的故事
A tribute to the everlasting grace of God.
作为礼物献给永恒仁慈的上帝
I can assure you, Your Holiness,
我保证 陛下
if you move your accounts from the Medici Bank...
如果您能把您的存款从美第奇银行...
to my own, you'll have all the funds you need.
转到我的银行里来 您就能获得充足的资金
This will require more than funds.
这不只需要资金
Resurrection requires death.
重生需要毁灭
And in this case,
现在
the sacrifice for Rome's rebirth
罗马的重生
will be Florence.
需要牺牲佛罗伦萨
However, the Medici have certain capabilities we are unsure we can best.
可是 我们不知道能否击败美第奇家族
We've tried a frontal assault.
我们已经尝试过一次正面进攻了
We may need you to develop
我们需要你进行一些
other... less direct contingencies.
其它的... 暗中破坏
The Medicis are the reason
美第奇家族
Florence is a sanctuary for sorcerers and... sodomites.
把佛罗伦萨变成了巫师和鸡奸者的避难所
They've turned my city away from the Lord.
他们在这城里亵渎上帝
Together, Holy Father, we will turn it back.
神父 我们要一起挽救这座城
Now gather your men, Girolamo.
召集你的部下 捷洛拉莫
You've a role to play in this as well.
你也有任务要做
He's been with our family his entire life.
他一生都和咱的家族在一起
He taught us our letters.
是他教我们识的字母
I don't care if he held your prick when you first took a piss.
我不管他抱没抱过你尿尿
Becchi is a spy and a traitor.
贝奇无疑是间谍和叛徒
His brother-in-law carries epic debts
他的姐夫欠了大笔债
which could only be met with the Roman scudos we found.
只有我们查获的罗马银币才能偿还
We broke the cipher in dozens of letters he hid.
我们破解了他藏匿信件的密文
Each one more incriminating than the last.
发现一封比一封罪孽深重
Now is not the time to show mercy.
现在不是仁慈的时间
So we're jailing old friends while making new friends with lunatics like Da Vinci.
所以我们把老朋友抓起来 和疯子达芬奇交朋友
Our grandfather made friends with lunatics.
我们祖父也和疯子交过朋友
Brunelleschi was one and he created the most majestic cathedral in Europe.
布鲁内列斯基也是疯子 可他建造了欧洲最雄伟的教堂
If you believe Becchi betrayed us,
要是你相信贝奇会叛变
it's you who's gone mad.
那你才是疯了
Lorenzo!
洛伦佐!
No! No, please!
不要! 求求你!
Tell me, are you familiar with Abraham's prayer for Sodom and Gomorrah?
告诉我 你知道亚伯拉罕对所多玛和蛾摩拉城的祷告是什么吗?
How many righteous people did Abraham initially promise
他一开始承诺能在两座罪恶之城里
he would find in those blighted cities?
找到多少正直的人?
20?
二十个?
Unfortunate.
很不幸
No! Please!
不! 求求你!
And your answer?
你说是多少?
No? No?
不知道? 不知道?
No idea?
不知道吗?
Are there no faithful in this forsaken place
这破地方没有忠诚的人了吗
or are you all damned?
还是所有人都被诅咒了?
You. Stand.
你 站起来
Let us pray you know the right reply.
我们期望你知道答案
What?
多少?
50! Signor.
五十人! 先生
You are correct.
答对了
You will deliver this message to the Medicis.
你把这封信带给美第奇家族
It contains, in exacting detail,
里面详细描述了
the horrors witnessed here today.
今天这里发生的事情
Why in God's name are we here, Riario?
瑞阿里奥 我们到底来这干嘛?
Tell me, Captain, how much did you give the Medicis for your coat?
告诉我 队长 美第奇家族卖给你这件大衣多少钱?
I bought it in Rome, not Florence.
我在罗马买的 不是佛罗伦萨
Every dyed fabric in Europe uses alum from these mines
欧洲所有的布料都要用这里的明矾矿
to fix the dye.
来稳固着色
Did you know, Pope Pius II
你知道吗 教皇庇护二世
gave this mining concern to the Medicis
把这里的矿产赐给美第奇家族
in return for forgiveness of papal debt.
以偿还教皇的债务
And since then, every frock, sheet and shirt
从那以后 每交易一件连衣裙 床单和衬衫
has had a portion of its price going to Florence.
佛罗伦萨都会赚到一部分提成
Today we killed three birds with one stone.
今天我们一举三得
We took back what was rightfully Rome's.
我们夺回了罗马的矿产
We eliminated a lucrative source of Medici income
我们铲除了美第奇的一笔收入来源
and most importantly...
最重要的是...
we sent a message.
我们送出了战函
This is an art, this pursuit.
这简直是在复制艺术品
I like just making one of something.
我只喜欢创作
Well, you'd better get used to it. We've got plenty more copies to go.
你最好习惯点 我们还有好多要生产呢
What is it that I'm getting used to?
我要习惯什么?
Making each soldier's death indistinguishable from the last?
习惯杀人变得麻木吗?
Leonardo, you're needed at the palace.
莱昂纳多 请到宫殿来一下
You playing errand boy now, Father?
你当起跑差了 老爸?
In these traitorous times, we fill any role required.
在国难关头 我们要听从征召
Come on. The Medicis are none of them patient men.
快点 美第奇家族可没耐心等你
Not you two.
你们不能来
This is state business, not a sideshow.
这是国家大事 非同小可
If you are in this room,
你们能坐在这里
it is because you reside in my innermost circle of trust.
是因为你们是我最信任的人
And if you are in my circle,
我信任你们
it is because we share a common vision for Florence.
是因为我们对佛罗伦萨有共同的期望
A city that will be remembered for centuries
我们希望佛罗伦萨可以被世代铭记
as a cynosure of innovation and artistry.
永为创新和艺术的焦点
I have received word from Tolfa, Commander Quattrone,
我收到了托尔法镇夸特隆司令官的消息
that Count Riario has attacked our alum mine.
瑞阿里奥伯爵进攻了我们的明矾矿
This is a casus belli. An act of war.
这是对我们的宣战
It is easy to be for Florence in times of peace.
和平时期的佛罗伦萨很繁荣
Not so in times of war.
但战争时期不会
Those who cannot stand with us should leave.
有谁不能支持我们的 请离开
It is better to be a coward now than a traitor later.
现在当懦夫 总比将来叛国好
I recently lost my most trusted advisor to treachery.
我近日失去了最信任的顾问
He currently sits in the Bargello awaiting his fate on the wheel.
他现在正在狱里等待他的刑罚
In the Medici court, we punish treason
美第奇家族惩罚叛贼
and we reward service.
奖赏功臣
Would the young man who brought me this scroll please come forward.
带来这封信的年轻人 请上前来
So tell us, please, how did you come by the scroll?
请告诉我们 你是从哪拿到这信的?
A Tolfan miner, sir.
一个明矾矿工给我的 先生
Count Riario killed all but one
瑞阿里奥伯爵杀了所有人
whom he tasked with delivering the scroll.
只留下他一个人送来这封信
And would you tell us what it says?
你能告诉我们信的内容吗?
Riario has an army, sir.
瑞阿里奥有一支军队 先生
He intends to occupy Florence unless you do as Rome asks.
他要你对罗马俯首称臣 否则将占领佛罗伦萨
Did the miner convey this to you?
这是那矿工告诉你的?
He's a simple man, sir. I doubt he can read.
他是个平民 先生 我想他不认识字
So you broke the seal
所以你私拆了信封
and revealed its contents to others?
然后给其他人看了内容?
Arrest him.
逮捕他
- Warm up the wheel with his bones!  - Please, sir! No!
- 先拿他试试刑轮!  - 求求你 先生! 不要!
I will show no mercy to those who betray the Medici name.
对背叛美第奇家族的人我绝不留情
Each of you has a responsibility to this community.
在城里你们每个人都各负其责
To protect. To invent. To maintain order.
保护 发明和维护秩序
To support.
支持
To uphold the sacred honor of the Medici legacy.
维护美第奇的神圣荣誉
We all knew this day would come.
我们都知道 这一天迟早会到来
We will not submit.
我们不会屈服
We will fight.
我们要战斗
Alla Battaglia Firenze!
为佛罗伦萨而战!
I think I have a cat in my bag.
我也有嫌疑
Would you like to kick that, too?
你也要处决我 是吗?
Enough.
够了
A city that will be remembered for centuries to come,
一座被作为革新和艺术焦点的城市
as a cynosure for innovation and artistry.
将被铭记数百年
That's a direct quote from Becchi's counsel to you,
这是直接引用了在十九岁继承基业之前
when you were a shit-scared 19-year-old poet about to ascend the throne.
贝奇给你这个吓得要死的空想家的建议
- Not now.  - Yes, now.
- 现在别提  - 就要现在提
There's a difference between strength and cruelty, Lorenzo.
强硬和残忍是不一样的 洛伦佐
Leave cruelty to Sixtus and his brutes,
不要再用暴政了
or it won't be Rome...
不然就不是罗马...
it'll be our own people who move against us.
而是我们自己的人民起来对抗我们
Do me a kindness, brother.
帮我个忙 兄弟
When I ride out to meet Count Riario,
等我去见瑞阿里奥伯爵的时候
stay home.
守在家里
Ladies and gentlemen, I have here the shattered ankle bone of St Alibinus.
女士们先生们 我有圣阿里比诺斯破碎的脚骨
A single shard of which is guaranteed to protect,
一块小小的碎骨可以保佑远离
against all pirates and all ruffians.
所有的海盗和暴徒
And, for a few soldi more,
如果再多出几个铜钱
the fingers of the esteemed martyr St Bessus!
还可以买到受人尊敬的圣白苏烈士的手指!
- It's Bess-us, you idiot!  - Oh, piss off.
- 是"拜苏" 你个白痴!  - 哦 得了吧
- What causes this commotion?  - Who else wants some?
- 怎么这么多人?  - 还有谁要?
People have gathered for an execution.
人们是来看死刑的
Gentile Becchi wasn't meant to be brought up until the full moon.
金泰尔・贝奇应该等到满月才行刑的吧
No, not Becchi. A servant.
不 不是贝奇 是个随从
Thanks to him, word of Riario's incursion has spread like wildfire,
拜他所赐 瑞阿里奥的口信已经像野火一样散播开来
and Lorenzo wants to make an example.
所以洛伦佐要杀一儆百
The Confraternity of Death are such vultures.
看行刑的人们真是无情
Someone has to pray for the condemned.
要有人为罪犯祈祷
This is ugly business for a lady.
这不适合女士观看
No.
不
Even a lady must support the Medicis against spies.
就算是女士也要支持美第奇家族对抗间谍
God.
天啊
How long will this take?
这要执行多久?
It can last hours.
可能数小时
God help any man who betrays Lorenzo.
背叛洛伦佐的人都会受到神的庇护
What are you reading?
你在看什么?
A Book of Hours.
祈祷书
In the original Latin, no doubt.
肯定是拉丁文原版的
I always hated that language.
我一直很讨厌那种语言
As was evident in your studies.
从你的学习态度就能看出来
Perhaps you were simply a piss-poor teacher.
也许你是个糟糕的老师
Perhaps.
也许吧
I'm sorry it's come to this.
弄成这样 真的很抱歉
Mm.
嗯
Why didn't you tell us about your family's need for money.
你为什么不跟我们说你家需要钱
I would never have troubled you with my relatives' mishaps.
我不会以自己亲属的不幸来为你们添麻烦
But you would take coin from Rome?
却接受罗马的钱?
Ask yourself, my boy.
扪心自问 孩子
If money had motivated me, why wouldn't it have been spent already?
如果我被金钱所鼓动 为什么还不花掉?
Instead of lying conveniently in my quarters awaiting discovery.
就随便放在我的住所里 等着被发现
Along with the papal seals of Rome.
还带着罗马教皇的封印
I want to believe.
我也想相信你
You counseled my grandfather Cosimo. My father.
你辅佐了我的祖父科西莫 我的父亲
You've given your life in service to Florence.
你毕生都献给了佛罗伦萨
Always doing your best to protect the Medici name.
一直在尽心竭力守护美第奇家族之名
But when I am gone, Giuliano,
等我死后 朱利亚诺
I will no longer be able to provide such protection.
我将无法再提供这种保护
Are you innocent of these charges or not?
你是不是无辜的呢?
- Of course I am.  - Then why don't you fight them?
- 当然是  - 那你为什么不争辩?
Because your brother is incapable of listening.
因为你哥哥已经听不进劝告了
Lorenzo is consumed with wrath.
洛伦佐已经被怒气蒙蔽了
It blinds him to the dangers circling him.
让他无法察觉身边的危险
There is a traitor in our midst.
我们的人中有叛徒
After I am dead and Lorenzo lowers his guard,
等我死后 洛伦佐会放松警惕
the traitor will still be here.
而叛徒还在
People underestimate you, Giuliano.
人们会低估你 朱利亚诺
Yet that perceived weakness makes you uniquely suited,
而这种观念使你特别适合
to flushing out a spy from cover.
从暗处抓出间谍
Look after your brother.
照顾好你哥哥
He needs you. Now more than ever.
他比以往更需要你
Riario will advance from the south,
瑞阿里奥会穿过瓦达诺谷
through the Valdarno Valley.
从南面进攻
We'll place weapons on all sides,
我们会在侧面布置武器
but the majority will meet his men here.
不过大部队会在这里交手
We'll be outnumbered. They'll be outgunned.
我们会占人数优势 武器超越他们
With ten guns? Are you certain?
就靠十门炮? 你确定吗?
We're casting more muskets.
我们在铸造更多大炮
I promise you you'll never have to fire them.
我保证 你根本用不着开炮
Sometimes...
有时候...
when all your enemy knows is killing,
当你的敌人只顾着杀戮的时候
a simple deception can suffice.
一个小骗局就能奏效
Riario is far more clever than you think, DaVinci.
瑞阿里奥比你想象的要聪明得多 达芬奇
Your wit won't get us out of this one.
你的智慧无法帮我们解开这个局
Only your weapons will.
不过你的武器可以
And I promise you they will fire.
而且我保证会开炮的
- Magnifico!  - Commander.
- 大人!  - 指挥官
- Artista.  - War engineer, actually.
- 艺术家  - 其实是战争工程师
That's a very handsome stallion you have there.
你骑的马很好啊
- Andalusian, no?  - Mm.
- 安达卢西亚种吗?  - 是
Given to me personally by Queen Isabella of Castile.
卡斯提尔的伊莎贝拉女王私人赏赐给我的
I've heard of these Andalusians.
我听说过这些安达卢西亚马
I understand the breed's prone to ischemic diseases,
我知道这马更容易得缺血性疾病
reduced blood flow, especially to the intestines,
降低血流速度 尤其是肠系统
which can lead to some unfortunate anal blockage.
会导致肛塞
Undoubtedly, you're used to the smell of shit following you wherever you go.
显然你已经习惯如影随形的马粪味了
Hmm.
哼
In an effort to avoid further bloodshed,
为了避免更大的杀戮
his Eminence has extended a list of demands.
大人提出了一些要求
First, Florence will formally embrace into its bosom,
首先 佛罗伦萨必须正式接受
Francesco Salviati as Archbishop of Pisa.
弗朗西斯科・萨尔维亚蒂出任比萨大主教
Second, the Medici Bank will forgive the Holy See of all debts.
其次 美第奇银行必须清空所有圣座的债务
And third, you will release,
再次 还要解除
certain artisans from their contractual obligations,
某些工匠的债务合约
so that they might employ their gifts,
让他们可以把自己的才华
in service of His Holiness's new chapel.
使用在圣座的新教堂上
And in which artist is His Holiness interested?
圣座需要哪些艺术家?
One... Pietro Perugino.
一个叫... 彼得・佩鲁吉诺
One Sandro Botticelli.
一个叫桑德罗・波提切利
- Oh, Jesus...  - Ooh.
- 天啊...  - 还有
Leonardo DaVinci.
莱昂纳多・达芬奇
I'd rather have my testicles gnawed off by conger eels.
我宁愿让鳗鱼咬掉我的蛋蛋
- Well, that can be arranged.  - And if we don't capitulate?
- 这要求可以满足  - 我们要是不答应呢?
My forces will occupy Florence.
我的部队将会占领佛罗伦萨
My guns will cut your men to ribbons.
我的大炮会把你的人炸成碎片
Your fabled pipe organ muskets?
你那些传说中的转轮炮?
Well, yes, they will cut down some of them, but not all.
是的 可以炸死一些 不过不是全部
Thanks to Giuliano's bumbling,
感谢朱利亚诺
I was aware that you possessed ten guns,
我得以知道你们铸造了十门炮
and given that I've observed them,
通过我对它们的观察
I simply deduced their cyclic rate of fire.
我简单地推算了它们的循环射速
Between them, they're capable of launching,
每一次装填后可以进行
33 volleys comprising 333 discharges.
33次齐射 共333颗炮弹
Now, let's... Let's assume that...
现在... 我们假设...
two-thirds of them hit their mark.
其中有三分之二击中了目标
But what happens while your brave militiamen are reloading?
不过你们的人在重新装填的时候会怎么样呢?
My remaining 400 ride out.
我剩下的四百铁骑会进攻
And, yes, we will use your precious Florentines as target practice.
对 是的 以你们珍贵的人民作为目标
You face a walled city, Riario.
你面对的是一座坚城 瑞阿里奥
We can hold you off for six months at the least.
我们至少可以抵御你们半年
It takes but one person to open the gates from the inside.
只需要一个内应就能打开坚城
Do you truly believe that in those months,
你真的相信在这半年间
the call of the Holy Father,
圣座的召唤
won't be honored by a single soul in Florence?
无法感召佛罗伦萨的任何一个灵魂吗?
You have 24 hours to ponder the Holy Father's offer.
你有24小时考虑圣座的条件
Enjoy your day.
祝你们愉快
We need more guns, DaVinci.
我们需要更多的炮 达芬奇
Our lives depend on it.
我们的性命决定于此
Shouldn't we be building guns,
我们不是应该铸造大炮
or at least preparing for the invasion?
或者至少准备防御进攻吗?
- I'm sketching.  - Pomegranates.
- 我在画草图  - 不过是石榴的
Nothing escapes you.
没什么能逃过你的眼睛
Count Riario is nearly upon us.
瑞阿里奥伯爵就快进攻了
I know damn well where Riario is!
我当然知道瑞阿里奥要来了!
- What are we doing here?  - I wonder about that myself.
- 我们在这做什么?  - 我自己也纳闷
Excuse us, Signora.
请原谅 夫人
You're rather careless with your sketches, Artista.
你对自己的草图也不认真 艺术家
You left a sheaf of them in my husband's study.
有一些忘在我丈夫的书房里了
Shouldn't you be laboring for the security of Florence?
你不是应该为佛罗伦萨的安全服务的吗?
There's something about this pomegranate. I can't define it yet.
石榴上还有些问题 目前还没有解决
But the Greeks teach us everything can be everything.
不过希腊人告诉我们任何事情都可以变化
And everything can be turned into everything else.
任何事物之间都可以互相转化
If we can't see the pattern in God's architecture,
如果我们看不到其中的结构
it's because we're not looking closely enough.
那只是因为我们观察得还不够近
Would you like your sketches back?
你还要你的草图吗?
Of all of Lorenzo's treasures,
洛伦佐所有的藏品里
it was this bit of carved stone that caught your eye.
只有这个小东西吸引了你的眼球
Has your husband ever mentioned it to you? Where it came from.
你丈夫给你说过吗? 它是从何而来?
I believe he inherited it.
我估计是继承的遗产
Perhaps from a man in the next room.
可能就是从隔壁房间的那个人
A magician.
一个魔术师
Lorenzo's grandfather. Cosimo.
这是洛伦佐的祖父科西莫
He ruled this city without ever holding office.
他连办公室都不需要就能治理这座城市
Oh, there's something about him.
哦 他确实有一套
You're welcome to study him at any time.
随时欢迎你来研究他
But for now I'd rather you returned to your guns. No?
不过现在我希望你能接着铸造大炮 好吗?
I didn't come to Florence to live under Roman rule.
我来佛罗伦萨不是为了屈从于罗马统治的
DaVinci.
达芬奇
A treat. For indulging me.
作为回报 请笑纳
Thank you for meeting with me,
感谢你能与我见面
especially with all the concerns about Rome.
特别是罗马正在咄咄相逼
I know this is unorthodox, but circumstances forced my hand.
我知道这不好 可事情发展至此 我别无他法
You know what's happened to Becchi.
你也知道贝奇的事了
The accusations that have been made.
指控已经成立
I don't believe he's a traitor.
我不相信他是叛徒
What do you want me to do?
你想让我怎么做?
Clarice has already agreed to advocate for Becchi.
克拉丽斯已经准备好支持贝奇了
You own the other half of my brother's heart. Will you do the same?
你掌控着我哥哥另一半的心 你也能这么做吗?
Are you so sure he's innocent?
你确定他是无辜的?
I believe we can prove it.
我相信可以证明这一点
Becchi has been giving me counsel.
贝奇已经给了我建议
Working with him, I know we can trap the real traitor.
跟他合作 我觉得我们可以抓出真正的叛徒
Please, Signora.
求你 夫人
Temperature's right.
炉温正常
Leo.
莱昂
The fat-kidneyed foreman requires your help.
肾脏肿大的那个工头需要你帮助
What do we know of Lorenzo's ancestors?
我们对洛伦佐的祖先了解多少?
His father was a good, but sickly, man.
他父亲是个好人 不过不健康 伙计
Who lived in the shadow of his father... Cosimo.
生活在他父亲的阴影之下... 科西莫
Wow. Really? How in fuck does this matter?
喔 是吗? 这他妈的有什么关系?
Rome's mercenaries are upon us.
罗马的佣兵已经兵临城下了
Clarice Orsini gave me this today.
克拉丽斯・奥尔西尼今天给我的
She said Lorenzo inherited it.
她说是洛伦佐继承来的
You're exhausted. Look at you.
你是累坏了 看看你
Fixating on bric-a-brac when we need more guns. It's insane.
在我们需要更多大炮的时候还在研究这个小玩意 简直疯了
The keys on it are identical to the ones from the Jew.
它手里的钥匙和犹太人那把是一样的
The Vault of Heaven. The Book of Leaves.
天穹 叶之书
How do the Medicis figure into it all?
美第奇怎么会知道这些?
Leo, I just don't see how a fucking mantelpiece antique,
莱昂 我就是不明白一个壁炉台上的古董
keeps Riario's swords from our fucking necks.
怎么能从瑞阿里奥剑下拯救我们的脖子
Christ, Zo. Can you just drop it for one minute?
天啊 琐罗 你就不能安生一会?
Do you have to prove your ignorance so damn often?
一定要这么频繁得证明自己的无知吗?
When the Byzantine Empire used the first cannons,
当拜占庭帝国围攻君士坦丁堡第一次使用大炮
against the Ottomans during the siege of Constantinople,
对付土耳其人的时候
the Turks were forced to flee.
土耳其人溃退了
30 years later, they returned with cannons of their own.
30年后 他们带着自己的大炮回来了
Bigger cannons.
更大的大炮
And after a 55-day siege left such destruction...
经过55天的围攻之后...
that the city will never be the same.
城市已经面目全非
Constantinople fell.
君士坦丁堡沦陷
Then we've always got to make sure we've got the biggest cannon.
那么我们就要一直保证自己拥有更大的大炮
Oh...
哦...
It never ends.
永无止境
Unless...
除非...
Unless I end it here.
除非我在这里终结它
Don't! That will cause an explosion!
住手! 会爆炸的!
Don't! Aargh!
住手! 啊!
Maestro, what have you done?
大师 你都做了些什么?
Sealed our fucking fate.
把我们的命运锁死了
Bless me, Father, for I have sinned.
请宽恕我 神父 原谅我的罪恶
How long has it been since your last confession?
你上一次忏悔是多久前了?
I'm... embarrassed to say.
我... 羞于启齿
Nearly a year.
快一年了
Oh.
哦
I have spoken with many shamed penitents tonight, child.
我今晚已经跟很多忏悔者谈过了 孩子
The wheel reminds people of the punishments,
刑轮让人们想到了惩罚
awaiting those not reconciled with Our Father.
还在等待着那些没有向圣父忏悔的灵魂
It's horrid.
太可怕了
I fear I myself drive someone toward a similar agony.
我恐怕亲手把别人送进了同样的酷刑
Every daughter of Eve faces the same dilemma.
夏娃的每位女儿都面对这同样的窘境
I have been untrue.
我不诚实
And now someone else is suffering for it.
现在却是别人在为此受苦
And he will endure unimaginable pain...
而且他要承受无法想象的痛苦...
- and it's my fault.  - If I may.
- 都是因我的错  - 请原谅
I have heard something of the state of your marriage.
我听说过一些关于你婚姻的传言
If you can offer up, even the smallest,
如果你能给予 哪怕是最小的
the tenderest bit of mercy,
最轻微的宽容
I have no doubt it will be taken very well.
我肯定会你会得到回报的
- Mercy has its risks.  - And rewards.
- 宽容是要冒险的  - 却能得到报答
Liar!
骗子!
"Good people of Florence, the Medicis are leading you to death."
"佛罗伦萨的良民们 美第奇家族在带领你们走向死亡"
You have to give Riario some credit.
你们一定要赞扬一下瑞阿里奥
He knows how to intimidate his prey.
他知道如何恐吓他的猎物
People say Riario has 2,000 men to burn the city.
据说瑞阿里奥带了两千人来屠城
I heard 3,000.
我听说有三千人
The city will be safe. I'll make sure of it.
城市会没事的 我来保证这一点
Pride is a deadly sin, Artista.
骄傲是一种以命相抵的罪恶 艺术家
Il Capitano!
队长!
I didn't take you for a religious zealot.
我没想到你还是个虔诚的教徒
A bully and an asshole, yes. A zealot?
一个恃强凌弱的混蛋 没错 还虔诚?
It's...
只是...
I'm zealous about my family.
我对自己的家庭虔诚
We pray every night that you're not leading this city to destruction.
我们每晚都在祈祷你不要把这座城市带往灭亡
What? I have that much power, do I?
什么? 我有那么大的力量 真的?
We've had nothing but trouble since you talked your way into the Medici court.
自从你牵扯上美第奇家族 我们增加的只有麻烦
Perhaps God is on the Count's side in this business.
也许是因为就此事来说上帝站在家族这边
I don't believe in any god,
任何与那个空想家为伍的神明
who would side with that pig's bladder.
都不值得我信仰
You blaspheme.
你在亵渎神灵
Men like you artistic perverts are turning Florence into Gomorrah.
像你这样的神经艺术家正在把佛罗伦萨变成蛾摩拉(圣经中的罪恶之都)
You're beating a quick path to the everlasting bonfire,
你正走在通往不灭业火的捷径
and dragging us all with you.
还拖着我们跟你一起
I'll send you to the bonfire even sooner.
我可以更快得直接把你送进业火
I know you're a better swordsman than I, DaVinci.
我知道你剑术比我高超 达芬奇
Still...
不过...
I've struck the bone, eh?
我戳中了你的软肋 是吧?
Do you really want to blunt the edge of your blade on me
在你需要利刃对付瑞阿里奥的时候
when you may need it sharp for Riario?
真的想在我身上砍钝自己的刀锋吗?
You're drunk, Leonardo.
你喝多了 莱昂纳多
Come on!
来啊!
Oh, my God.
天啊
Jesus.
上帝
I heard what happened at the metal works.
我听说了铸造作坊的事情
You're better than this, Leonardo.
你不是这样的 达芬奇
I thought I could save Florence. I thought...
我觉得自己可以拯救佛罗伦萨 我觉得...
my talents would be enough, but they aren't.
我的才华已经足够 可惜不是的
I've got nothing.
我一无所有
And because of me,
也因为我
tomorrow morning, Lorenzo will be forced to surrender.
明早洛伦佐只能被迫投降
No, please. Florence and Rome have been at it since before you were born.
别这么说 佛罗伦萨和罗马在你出生之前已经如此
- It's politics.  - No, it's...
- 这是政治  - 不 这是...
It's personal.
是私事
I have something they want.
我拥有他们想要的东西
Yes. Your talent.
对 你的才华
The Pope wants my talent.
教皇想要我的才华
Riario wants my key.
瑞阿里奥想要我的钥匙
- What key?  - The key from...
- 什么钥匙?  - 那把钥匙...
Nothing.
没什么
Come here.
过来
If something burdens you...
如果你感到负担...
maybe it's better just to let it go.
也许放开它会更好些
Wait. Wait.
等等 慢点
What?
怎么了?
That's what Lorenzo requires of me.
洛伦佐就是这样要求我的
Why did you destroy your guns?
你为什么要炸毁自己的大炮?
Lorenzo.
洛伦佐
He looked me in the eye and told me I was an inventor.
他看着我的眼睛告诉我 我是个发明家
But this isn't invention. This is...
可这不是发明 这是...
It's escalation. I build five, they build 50.
这是复制 我铸造五门 他们铸造五十门
You might be the loveliest man I've ever known.
你估计是我见过最可爱的人
Hey.
嘿
Why do you say it with such sadness?
你为什么说的时候如此悲伤?
Maybe it's because I think none of us are worthy of you.
也许是因为我觉得我们谁也配不上你
Why the pomegranates?
为什么研究石榴?
I don't know yet.
还不知道
Do you know...
你知道...
Now... Hades tricked Persephone into eating pomegranates,
其实... 在珀尔塞福涅离开冥界时
when she left the underworld.
是冥王骗她吃下了石榴
She said that their magic forced her to return to him.
她说是魔法迫使她回到他的身边
It's true.
是真的
You should take one with you when you go.
你走的时候应该带个走
It's not magic that binds me to you, Leonardo.
不是魔法让你我相遇相交的 莱昂纳多
I hope you kill that bastard Riario.
我希望你能杀了瑞阿里奥那个杂种
Leonardo!
莱昂纳多!
Oh, so you have the gall to remain in Florence?
你还有胆留在佛罗伦萨?
You're either brave or unimaginably stupid.
你到底是勇敢还是傻到不透气
A bit of both.
都算是吧
You sabotage our efforts. Why?
你毁掉了我们的努力 为什么?
The guns wouldn't have ended this.
大炮无法终结这一切
With all your experience in waging war, you decided that, did you?
就凭你这点战争的经验 你就认定这样了 是吗?
You little...
你个...
Fuck!
该死!
I can't believe I trusted you.
真难以置信 我竟然信了你
You, a bastard. A charlatan. A peddler of knick-knacks!
你这个混蛋 骗子 地摊贩子!
My brother was right. I was a fool to believe in you. A fool!
我弟弟说得对 我相信你实在太傻了 太傻了!
My only recourse is to offer myself as Riario's hostage,
我唯一能做的是自己去做瑞阿里奥的人质
and I'll have to pray that if I put myself at his mercy,
还得祈祷能得到他的宽恕
that he will forego pillaging Florence.
让他不再劫掠佛罗伦萨
I'll have to pray that he'll grant Clarice and our children safe passage.
我还得祈祷他能保证克拉丽斯和我们孩子的安全
isn't struck from the streets!
不会从街上被清理掉!
You gather what little you hold dear and you meet me in the field.
你收拾好自己的收藏跟我去见面的地方吧
I want you by my side when I am forced to accept Rome's terms.
在我被迫接受罗马的条件的时候 希望你能见证
And if Riario wants you...
而且如果瑞阿里奥想要你...
he can fucking have you.
就他妈的把你给他
Nico, it is good to see you again.
尼科 很高兴再见到你
I trust your hand is mending.
估计你的手快好了吧
Let us go straight to the terms of surrender.
我们直接谈谈投降的条件吧
Indeed.
好
I have certain...
我确定...
require certain assurances.
需要一些保证
Florence and its citizens are my chief concern...
因为佛罗伦萨和这里的人民是我最关切的...
Sorry. Sorry.
抱歉 等等
Um, we are clear whose surrender we're discussing here?
呃 我们明确了是哪一方要投降对吧?
It's yours.
是你们
DaVinci...
达芬奇...
Nico, would you show the Count and Captain General our gift?
尼科 给伯爵和司令看看我们的礼品吧?
Now, since you'd calculated the capacity of my guns,
看吧 既然你已经推算了我大炮的射速
I've endeavored to improve Florence's odds.
我也试着改进了佛罗伦萨的装备
It's a question of mathematics.
只是简单的数字问题
How to pack a group of spheres in the most economic fashion.
怎样用最节省的方式填装所有的弹丸
And since nature always employs the most efficient means to achieve her ends,
既然大自然总是使用最有效的方式达到目的
I've taken inspiration from her.
我就从中获得了灵感
I call it the cluster bombard.
我管这个叫集束炸弹
The casing houses a grouping of smaller explosives,
炮弹中是一包更小的炸弹
an Archimedean solid,
阿基米德体形态
which is separated by iron spacers.
由钢制层分离
So when the bombard lands, it fragments into a fountain of shrapnel.
所以当炮弹着地的时候 弹片形成一个喷泉
I estimate one bombard could take out a dozen of your men and their mounts.
我估计每颗炸弹可以干掉你一打的人还有他们的坐骑
Now, I know what you're thinking.
我知道你在想什么
You're thinking, "Well, fair enough.
你在想 "哦 还可以
A bombard's really only as good as one's ability to lob it."
炸弹只有能够装填发射才能发挥作用"
So, fair enough. You'd be right.
对 很对 你想得不错
However...
不过...
Zo!
琐罗!
Let's go.
动手
Impressive.
很有说服力
But how do I know that contraption even works?
我怎么能相信你的发明是能用的?
Allow me to demonstrate on a smaller scale.
请允许我用一个小型的模型演示
First, we light the bombard.
首先 我们把炮弹点燃
Then we fire it... like so.
然后发射... 就这样
The real, full-scale bombard doesn't carry fireworks, of course.
当然真正满载的炸弹 装的不是烟火
We will rain flame and destruction down on your men,
我们将用火焰和杀伤力笼罩你的军队
recalling Biblical devastation of old.
让他们想起圣经传说中的毁灭
The peasants will pick the bone fragments of your men
你的人散落在这片土地上的骸骨碎片
from these fields for decades to come.
农民们估计要花几十年才能捡完
You... everything you've accomplished, will fade from memory.
你... 赢得的一切 将会从记忆中被清除
Whereas our victory will be lionized for centuries.
反而我们的胜利将会被传承数百年
Perhaps.
也许
Or perhaps regardless of what happens today,
也许今天发生的事情不算什么
the opposite tale will be told, or no tale at all.
传说的会是另一个故事 或者没有故事
You see, a man once told me...
是这样 曾经有一个人告诉我...
History is a lie.
历史只是谎言
Well played, Artista.
干得好 艺术家
You'd... You'd do well to remember, though,
你... 虽然你记性不错
that a war is waged on many fronts.
战争有很多的方面
Hyah! Hyah!
驾! 驾!
You pulled off quite a feat, Leonardo.
解除了好大的威胁 莱昂纳多
I would have liked to see it fire. Imagine the carnage.
我真想看它开炮 想象这个残杀
Rome would have been holding funerals for months.
罗马估计要连续办几个月的葬礼
The crossbow it doesn't actually work.
这个弩其实根本不能用
It's more a feat of art than weaponry.
这其实不是武器 而是一件艺术品
This sham...
这个赝品...
is the work of drunken artists.
是宿醉艺术家的作品
They're more skilled in stage props than armaments.
表演的意义远大于真正的武器价值
How on earth can we have built the real device in one night?
一夜之间我们怎么可能造出来真正的装备?
Even if I had, the drawstring needed to fire the damn thing would have been ludicrous.
就算造出来了 弹射这玩意的皮筋力量也荒唐的可笑
- Look at it.  - You wagered our fate on a bluff?
- 你看吧  - 你把我们的命运当做儿戏的赌注?
- I did.  - You only bought us a temporary reprieve.
- 是  - 那你只是为我们赢得了暂时的喘息
You can't keep on bluffing Rome forever.
你不可能唬住罗马一辈子
Can't we?
不能吗?
Life's precious, Lorenzo.
生命宝贵 洛伦佐
Even a traitor's.
叛徒亦如是
I believe...
我相信...
it was your grandfather, Cosimo...
是你祖父科西莫...
who voiced a pertinent sentiment.
发表过相关的意见
"We read that we ought to forgive our enemies.
"我们知道应该原谅我们的敌人
We do not read that we ought to forgive our friends."
却不知道要原谅我们的朋友"
Sorry, brother. I was just having a rest.
抱歉 兄弟 我只是稍稍休息一下
Have you come to minister to the condemned?
你是来帮囚犯做忏悔的?
Right.
好
I appreciate the visit but I've already made peace with my maker.
我感谢你的来访 不过我已经接受了这一切
Signora.
夫人
You.
你
You're the one that slipped those documents into my quarters.
是你把那些文件放进了我的房间
How long have they owned you?
你变节多久了?
A few years.
几年了
Then they approached you...
那他们收买你...
Before Lorenzo and I were involved.
是在我与洛伦佐在一起之前
Whatever promise they made, they will not honor it.
不管他们承诺了什么 都不会兑现的
You have no idea,
你对我的处境
of my circumstances.
一无所知
There's more to this than Florence or Rome,
这不仅关乎佛罗伦萨 罗马
or my life.
还有我的性命
Why are you here, Signora?
你来干什么 夫人?
Because I do not wish to see you broken on a wheel.
因为我不想看到你被钉在刑轮上活活打死
What?
什么?
Hemlock.
毒芹
How?
怎么会?
A weapon stolen from the Secret Archives in the Vatican.
从罗马教廷密室偷来的一件武器
A misericorde, modified with a single dose of poison.
这一件带着一针毒剂
Its bite is almost never noticed.
几乎感觉不到疼痛
So no evidence will arise,
不会有证据指向
implicating Lorenzo's lover.
洛伦佐的爱人
Consider it mercy.
请当做是我的慈悲
This is the fastest and most painless death I can offer.
这是我能提供的最迅速 最没有痛苦的死法
And I will see that it takes.
我需要亲眼见证
This isn't mercy.
这不是慈悲
This is you... tying off loose ends.
只是你... 在灭口
Rome chose well.
罗马的选择是高明的
- Guard!  - I'm sorry.
- 卫兵!  - 抱歉
I wish there was another way.
我也希望还有其他的办法
Becchi!
贝奇!
Guards!
卫兵!
Guards, quickly!
卫兵 快!
Hemlock.
是毒芹
- Becchi would not have done this.  - The vial speaks for itself.
- 贝奇不会自杀的  - 证据确凿
And you have a history of not believing things,
而且你也已经习惯不相信
that Becchi has clearly done.
贝奇所做的事情
Question is, brother,
问题在于 弟弟
who brought Becchi this poison?
是谁给贝奇送来了毒药?
Was it someone who sympathizes with his plight?
会不会是支持他的人?
If I were to defy you, brother, I wouldn't don a mask to do it.
如果是我的话 哥哥 我不会带着面具的
But what do you care?
你还在乎什么?
The traitor is dead, Florence is secure,
叛徒死了 佛罗伦萨安全了
and you've a war engineer to fete.
你还要给个战争工程师奖赏
All is well in the Republic tonight.
最好是在今晚的会上
The names and charges written on this paper,
这份命令上写的名字和指控
require our immediate attention as Priori.
要求我们立刻提起最高注意
An anonymous denunciation?
匿名告发信?
The author's unimportant.
告发人不重要
This matter demands investigation.
此事需要调查
I'd caution you to consider who will be implicated.
我要提醒你考虑牵涉其中的人
As Priori, you are duty bound to uphold the law,
作为执法者 你们有责任维护律法
unconcerned by who whomever it may incriminate.
不管涉及到谁
Interrogate the victim mentioned here, Captain.
提审这里提到的人 队长
Once he confirms the charges, make your arrest.
他只要认罪 就逮捕他
Wow, look at you!
瞧瞧你!
Venetian breeches, bit of velvet, bit of brocade.
威尼斯马裤 带天鹅绒 带锦缎
Did you buy those with your Medici vouchers?
你用美第奇的奖赏买的?
What concern is it of yours?
你担心什么?
Who traded in chits to muster the men,
是谁打白条召集众人
to sneak your phony crossbow out of the city? Hm?
把你的大假弩拉出城的? 忘了?
Who assembled all the pieces in the middle of the night, risking his life?
是谁半夜冒着生命危险 把它组装起来的?
Cos it wasn't Nico. Yet somehow that little bull's pizzle,
因为不是尼科 结果那个小屁孩子都受邀
wins an invitation to Lorenzo's palazzo and I don't.
去洛伦佐的宫殿了我都没有
Nico hasn't been arrested a dozen times for lewd behavior,
尼科没有因为下流行径 偷窃
and pickpocketing, grave robbing.
或者挖坟掘墓被逮捕过多次
I can't have you there tonight, Zo. Sorry.
我今晚不能带你去 琐罗 抱歉
These people...
得体对这些人...
decorum means everything to them.
意味着一切
Where is your guest of honor, Lorenzo?
你的贵宾在哪里 洛伦佐?
If we're to praise an artist, perhaps it should be Signor Botticelli.
如果是要表彰一位艺术家 那就应该是波提切利先生
At least he has blessed up with his presence.
因为至少他到场了
No need to honor someone who honors themselves so well, brother.
一个已经誉满全城的人不需要其它荣誉了 哥哥
Every time I find myself looking for DaVinci, he seems to have...
每次我发现自己在找达芬奇的时候 他都会...
vanished like smoke.
像烟雾一样消失
Is there a reason you're avoiding the party, Maestro?
你有什么原因要躲开聚会吗 大师?
It's being held in your honor.
大家都等着你呢
Something's needling me, Nico.
有事情困扰着我 尼科
Till I can discover what it...
等我发现这...
Ha!
哈!
Yes!
对了!
The old magician's laughing.
老魔术师的微笑
I'm an idiot.
我真是白痴
The symbols couldn't be clearer.
提示再明显不过了
I am a son of Earth and Starry Heaven.
我是大地与星空之子
I am thirsty. Please give me something to drink,
我渴了 求你了 从记忆之泉中
from the fountain of Memory.
取水给我喝
The invocation for the Sons of Mithras. Look.
密特拉之子的祷词 看
A bull pulling a plow.
牛在拉犁
Christian iconography but it's also the pagan symbol for Earth.
基督徒的插图 也是异教徒的大地标志
A star-filled heaven.
布满星星的天空
A chalice, symbolic of a fountain.
圣杯 象征着喷泉
And flowers. Ne M'oubliez Pas, in French.
还有花朵 花名是法语的
Forget-me-nots.
勿忘草
Memory.
记忆
Cosimo de Medici...
科西莫・美第奇...
was a Son of Mithras.
是密特拉之子
It's as if all my inquiries are converging.
看来我所有的疑问都汇聚到了一起
It's as if a grand web is being spun.
就像一张撒开的网
One so incalculably wide and ancient,
无法想象的广阔和古老
that I'm only now beginning to grasp its scope.
以至于我才刚刚目及导它的范围
I have proven myself to Lorenzo.
我已经向洛伦佐证明了自己
I've earned his trust.
赢得了他的信任
It's time for him to repay me in kind.
是时候让他用爱心回报我了
By doing what?
怎样?
By funding an expedition.
赞助一次探险
To the land indicated on the Jew's map.
去犹太人地图上指示的大陆
A ship, provisions for a journey.
一艘船 探险的补给
The Vault of Heaven is out there, Nico.
天穹就在那 尼科
It's harbing the Book of Leaves.
叶之书就在那里
All the knowledge it contains, I can hear it calling to me.
还有里面的知识 我能听到它在呼唤我
And the magician is leading me to it.
魔术师在指引我的路
My grandfather, Cosimo, had a dream.
我的祖父科西莫有一个梦想
That our streets and squares,
我们的街道和广场
would be a haven for science, art and learning.
应该是科学 艺术和求知的天堂
No son of Florence better represents those ideas,
最能代表这理想的佛罗伦萨子民
than Leonardo DaVinci.
就是莱昂纳多・达芬奇
I name you...
我赐你为...
Grand Master of the Order of St John the Baptist,
"施洗者约翰"之大师
patron saint of Florence.
佛罗伦萨的守护者
I give you the living embodiment of classical brilliance.
请允许我向你们介绍古典智慧的真实化身
Leonardo DaVinci.
莱昂纳多・达芬奇
Please, Maestro, won't you grant us a few words?
来吧 大师 给我们说几句吧?
Florence's greatest export has always been its ideas.
佛罗伦萨最大的产品就是灵感
Our Republic represents the cutting edge of inquiry.
我们的共和制代表着追求的前沿
We are inventing the future.
我们在发明未来
But we can only remain vital if we keep on pushing outwards,
但是只有不停追求才能保证我们一直生气勃勃
so I propose a bold new step.
所以我请求一个新的开始
I have learned of a land, your Magnificence, to the west.
我发现了一片大陆 殿下 在西面
It's largely uncharted but it's certain to contain wonders.
未曾表明过却一定蕴含着奇异
Now, with your patronage, I shall mount an expedition.
现在 得到您的资助 我想开始一次探险
We will voyage...
我们要驶向...
Captain Dragonetti, what is the meaning of this affront?
德拉戈奈蒂队长 这么无礼是要干什么?
My apologies, Signor.
抱歉 阁下
A grave accusation has been levied against one of your guests.
有一项挖坟掘墓的罪名落到了您一位宾客的头上
I know nothing of any accusations.
我对此一无所知
May I remind you, Nazzareno, that you answer to me.
请允许提醒你 纳扎雷诺 你是我的属下
Technically, I answer to the Signoria, your Magnificence.
准确来说 我是法度的属下 殿下
Of which you are but one voice.
您虽代表着法律 但也仅是一人之言
I couldn't dissuade them, Signor. It's protocol.
我不能无视法度 阁下 这是规矩
Our hands were tied.
我们只能服从
Go on then, Captain.
那继续吧 队长
It has come to the attention of the Officers of the Night,
此事已经引起了值夜的官员注意
by means of secret denunciation,
是通过匿名告发的方式
that one Leonardo di ser Piero DaVinci,
有一位叫莱昂纳多・达芬奇的人
has committed, in violation of the statutes of the Republic of Florence,
被认定违反了佛罗伦萨共和国的律法
and divine and natural law, the grievous act of sodomy.
神赐的自然律法 还犯有鸡奸罪
Said individual is to be immediately remanded...
此人需被立即羁押候审...
These are lies. This is slander!
那些是谎言 这是诽谤!
Whereupon he will remain,
所以他会被扣押
until the Magistrates ascertain his guilt or innocence.
直到治安官查清他有罪还是无罪
Should he be found guilty,
若是有罪
he will be led through the public squares to the Palace of Justice,
他将会被游街示众到刑场
and there be burned so that he dies...
然后火刑至死...
and his body is separated from his soul.
直到肉体与灵魂分离
No! You...
不! 你...
This is your work, Francesco.
这都是你做的 弗朗西斯科
I smell the Pazzi stench all over this charade.
我能闻到阴谋的恶臭
The denunciation is real, Lorenzo.
指控是真的 洛伦佐
We've a victim willing to testify.
我们有污点证人
No-one has been sentenced for this crime for more than 50 years.
已经有五十年没有人因为这项罪名被判刑了
And yet it's still on the statute books.
不过还是在律法之中
If you've issues with it, take it up with your forebear Cosimo.
如果你有意见 去找你先人科西莫说吧
Was it not he who revised Florence's constitution?
难道不是他修订了佛罗伦萨的宪法吗?
Or would you flout our fair Republic's laws as you see fit?
还是你要以自己的看法凌驾于我们共和制的法律之上?
I was under the impression we lived in a democracy.
我认为我们还是生活在一个共和的体制之下
- Not a dictatorship.  - Your wrists, Signor.
- 而不是独裁制  - 请伸手 先生
Told you that you take the quick path to the bonfire, Artista.
早跟你说了走在通往业火的捷径上了 艺术家